Guide to the H. K. Wilcox photographs, 1890-1915.
Wilcox, H. K. photographs, 1890-1915.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
H. K. Wilcox photographs, 1890-1915.
6372
H. K. Wilcox.
4.9 cubic ft.
Photographs.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Photographic albums containing photographs taken on trips to Egypt, Palestine, Syria, Turkey, Greece, Italy, Switzerland, France, England, the United States, Africa, Holland, Scotland, Ireland, Germany, and Algeria between 1897 and 1915. Also, loose photographs, lantern slides, and dry plate glass negatives documenting extensive travel from 1890.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Photographic albums containing photographs taken on trips to Egypt, Palestine, Syria, Turkey, Greece, Italy, Switzerland, France, England, the United States, Africa, Holland, Scotland, Ireland, Germany, and Algeria between 1897 and 1915. Also, loose photographs, lantern slides, and dry plate glass negatives documenting extensive travel from 1890. Also five diaries, 1870, 1873, 1878, 1897 and 1913 (in one volume) and 1905.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Wilcox, H. K.
Subjects:
Views.; Voyages and travels.
Places:
Europe; Africa; Middle East; United States
Form and Genre Terms:
Cyanotypes.; Dry collodion negatives.; Photograph albums.; Lantern slides.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Photo albums
  - Views of a Trip to Spain, Africa, Italy, Switzerland, France, Belgium, Holland, England, Wales, Scotland, and Ireland; Apr. 21-Oct. 26, 1894, 1894 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Scenes in Egypt, Palestine, Galilee, Syria, Turkey, Greece, and Italy, taken on a trip commencing Jan. 3 and ending May 24, 1900, 1900 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - California Tour, Feb. 3-Apr. 26, 1897 Florida Tour; Feb.-Apr. 1897, 1897 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Scenes along the Rhine; through Switzerland; by Auto through France, Brittany and Normandy and by Coach through Devonshire and Cornwall, England. June 9-Sept. 11, 1905, 1905 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Scenes in Madeira Islands, Gibraltar, Algiers, Africa, Nice, Mentone, Monte Carlo, San Remo, Rome, Florence, Venice, Vienna, Dresden, Berlin, Hamburgh, and Cuxhaven, 1913 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - California, 1915 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Nebraska, Florida, Georgia, Illinois, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Negative albums
  - Middle East, Greece, Italy, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Gibraltar, Italy, Switzerland, France, Belgium, Holland, England, Scotland, Ireland, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Photographs
  - Middle East, Syria, Scotland, France, Wilcox house, unidentified (Box 5)
  - St. John (New Brunswick), Collision between the Cromartyshire and the La Bourgogne, Halifax and Yarmouth (Nova Scotia), Quebec, St. Lawrence River, Camp Sable Exploration Survey Everglades, St. Augustine Florida, Long Key, Southern United States, Taylor River Expedition, Montmorency Falls, Prince Edward Island, Pasadena California, Massachusetts., 1898-1903 (Box 6)
- Lantern slides
  - Egypt (in a case) [3" x 4"] (Box 7)
- Glass negatives
  - Nos. 1-60 [4" x 5"] Wilcox family and home, friends (Graham, Crawford, Slauson), tennis players, Minneapolis houses, 1890 (Box 8)
  - Nos. 46-105 (46-60 duplicate numbers - not the same subjects) [4" x 5"] Wilcox family and friends, Canadian Islands, Jersey Heights, LaRue Lodge, Thousand Island Park, 1890 (Box 9)
  - Nos. 106-165 [4" x 5"] Wilcox family and friends, steamers and yachts, Phillipsburgh Mills, Rose Island, Indians, Emigrants at Central Square, 1890 (Box 10)
  - Nos. 166-225 [4" x 5"] Wilcox family and friends, West Point, Canada, LaRue, Ice Storm, Invitation to Wedding, 1890-1891 (Box 11)
  - Nos. 225-270 [4" x 5"] Wilcox family and friends, Westminster Park, LaRue, boats, Lattimer's Bay, 1891 (Box 12)
  - Nos. 271-330 [4" x 5"] Wilcox family and friends, LaRue, West Point (Nebraska), cowboys at Winnebago Reservation, Sious City, Chicago, 1891 (Box 13)
  - Nos. 331-390 [4" x 5"] Wilcox family and friends, Naval Review (New York City), St. Augustine and Jacksonville, Washington, D.C., 1892-1893 (Box 14)
  - Nos. 391-420 and 2 sets unidentified [4" x 5"] Wilcox family and friends, dogs, Minnehaha Falls, 1893-1894 (Box 15)
  - Peachland, N.C. (3 sets) and unidentified (1 set) [4" x 5"], 1898 (Box 16)
  - California and LaRue Lodge [4" x 5"], 1897 (Box 17)
  - House at 28 Grove Street and 3 sets unidentified [4" x 5"], n.d. (Box 18)
  - Unidentified [4" x 6"]; LaRue Lodge and unidentified [9" x 6"] (Box 19)
  - Nox. 1-40 [4" x 6"] (Box 20)
  - Diaries, 1870, 1873, 1878, 1897, 1905 and 1913 (Box 21)